<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-29T14:09:23-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">RocFri Portfolio</title><entry><title type="html">Yes, Finally Fonts!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/29/yes-fonts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yes, Finally Fonts!" /><published>2016-11-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/29/yes-fonts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/29/yes-fonts.html">&lt;h2&gt; Yes, Finally Fonts!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I hope my project site looks slightly better. Fonts didn’t want to render. For a while I wasn’t getting any error, then changed my import method and started getting CSP error. Followed the answer here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/33984908/google-fonts-violates-content-security-policy&quot;&gt; Thank you much Rolinh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That took about 5-7 focused hours to figure out, which isn’t too long in some respects but too long in a work environment. Making little sites, I’ve never come across that error before. I read up on CSP and it seems like a pretty good idea to implement from now on. The most frustrating thing, with this and many other little meta tags and tweeks is that support sites don’t show the context of the syntax.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="updates" /><summary type="html">Yes, Finally Fonts!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Impressions: Nuances of Things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/28/annoying-nuances.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Impressions: Nuances of Things" /><published>2016-11-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/28/annoying-nuances</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/28/annoying-nuances.html">&lt;p&gt;This site is being generated by Jekyll and all that comes with it short of SASS. I was very skeptical about Jekyll. It seemed like it’d be just as easy to make a static site the good ol’ fashion way, but I want to try the new and shiny stuff. Now I see how it’s generally more useful than I originally thought. Still I’m not really jumping up and down to use it for a plain old static site, but it does come in handy if you’re looking for something a little less heavy than WordPress or a CMS with a whole database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Github flavored variation of MD/Kramdown parser is not playing too well with block elements. Despite what troubleshooting I’ve tried to do, it doesn’t work. I’m pretty sure the conflict is with the CSS I have for my content. It’s easier for me to just write out the HTML by time I figure out how to make it behave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process of trying to make things work well together has been kind of a headache. It’s infinitely easier to run Ruby on Windows (this is hard? I mean… there are a few installers for Ruby on Windows these days). Anyway, the latest thing is getting Jekyll to show Google fonts. Then finding out there’s some security issue with the fonts or rather they’re being blocked because I didn’t specify google as a source. Not a problem I’ve had before. From a local standpoint, not sure why CSP would be interfering. Assuming it isn’t, I’m still unable to get Jekyll to render the fonts correctly, so I have to run them the good ol’ fashion way to see if I’m just misspelling or misplacing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything works at the HTML/CSS level.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="updates" /><summary type="html">This site is being generated by Jekyll and all that comes with it short of SASS. I was very skeptical about Jekyll. It seemed like it’d be just as easy to make a static site the good ol’ fashion way, but I want to try the new and shiny stuff. Now I see how it’s generally more useful than I originally thought. Still I’m not really jumping up and down to use it for a plain old static site, but it does come in handy if you’re looking for something a little less heavy than WordPress or a CMS with a whole database.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where I was at in November 2016</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/26/update-nov.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where I was at in November 2016" /><published>2016-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/26/update-nov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/2016/11/26/update-nov.html">&lt;h2&gt;Where I'm at&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;November 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Site…
&lt;br /&gt;
I’m still figuring out how to make Jekyll work with Kramdown and design elements. Locally, it isn’t panning out correctly. I was told to give Jekyll a try and so I have. I have a Windows computer, because flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem I really ran into with Jekyll was Gem compatibility and building Jekyll’s pre-made site with SASS since I don’t really care for SASS. This is solvable by running bundle and my other problems became solvable by updating my Gem version (to correct version and then to the new one) and making sure my paths were right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I design all my sites for an 8” tablet screen. Usually, looks good within approximately 2” difference in screens. Seeing as Jekyll is a static site generator I don’t have too much to worry about as far as JS and cross functionality, though I’ll be continually updating here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll write something up about my experience with Jekyll soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects…
&lt;br /&gt;
Around 7 months ago I set out to find a project to work on. My background is mostly web, so I figured that was a good starting point.,] I found a multitude of technologies and decided to start with WordPress. After numerous tutorials, I have some PHP/WP under my belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My projects are pretty small right now. I’m working on a site for someone I know and my plan is to finish what I started with WP before putting too much time into a new project. I’m still working on getting a good grasp on Ruby, Python and frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School…
&lt;br /&gt;
My undergrad degree was in humanities and I’ve always felt that wasn’t the best decision. I know there are plenty of ways to learn the coding skills I need to get a job, but the approaches I found felt a little short sited. I decided going back to school for a Masters in Software Engineering was a better option for me. There are a lot of great programs out there, but for depth and solid foundational knowledge, academia appeared to be the best choice. And some of the boot camp programs are just as much as costly as a Masters degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the school semester the bulk of my free time (I work full time too in a non-tech industry) goes to school work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="updates" /><summary type="html">Where I'm at
November 2016</summary></entry></feed>
